[{"question":"1. According to the accepted concept of hormone action, if receptor molecules are removed from target organs, then the target organ will:","a":"(a) not respond to the hormone.","b":"(b) continue to respond to hormone without any difference.","c":"(c) continue to respond to the hormone but in the opposite way.","d":"(d) continue to respond to the hormone but will require higher concentration.","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"glands is mediated through:","a":"(a) Hormones","b":"(b) Enzymes","c":" (c) Minerals","d":"(m (d) Vitamins","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"3. Ovulation in humans is controlled by:  fo FSHI and IT","a":"(a) FSH and LTH ","b":" (b) ESH and GH","c":"(c) LTH and LH ","d":" (d) FSH and LH","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":" Deficiency of vasopressin primarily results in:","a":"(a) Increased volume of urine Tricky","b":"(b) Decreased volume of urine","c":"(e) Excessive secretion of urochrome","d":"(d) Change in pH from acidic to alkaline range.","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"5. The first hormone artificially produced by genetically engineered bacteria is:","a":"(a) Insulin ","b":"b) Somatotropin ","c":" (c) Testosterone","d":" (d) Adrenaline","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"6.  Which endocrine gland stores its secretion in extracellular spaces before discharging it into blood? Tricky","a":"(a) Testis ","b":"(b) Pancreas","c":"(c) Thyroid","d":"(d) Adrenal ","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"7. Pineal body develops from:","a":"(a) Dorsal part of diencephalon","b":"(b) Ventral part of diencephalon","c":"(c) Ventral side of cerebellum","d":"(d) Lateral side of cerebrum","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"8.  If thyroxine is added in a beaker which has some small tadpoles then: Tricky","a":"(a) all tadpoles die.  ","b":"(b) they metamorphose very fast.","c":"(c) they develop small body. ","d":" (d) they develop a giant body.","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"9.  Which of the following hormones is a cholesterol- derivative?","a":"(a) Estrogen ","b":"(b) Prostaglandin ","c":"(c) Epinephrine","d":"(d) All of these ","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"  10. \"Upregulation\" of hormone receptors refers to:","a":"(a) increase in hormone receptor numbers with low hormone levels.","b":"(b) increase in hormone receptor numbers with high neurotransmitter levels.","c":"(e) increase in hormone levels produced by increase in hormone receptor numbers.","d":"(d) decrease in hormone levels produced by decrease in hormone receptor numbers.","hint":"","correct":"a"}]